[
   {
     "qno": 1,
"question": "Simplify: 3/4 ÷ 1/2",
"opa": "3/8",
"opb": "3/2",
"opc": "2/3",
"opd": "1/4",
"correctanswer": "2"
},
 {
     "qno": 2,
"question": "Solve: 5x − 2 = 18. What is x?",
"opa": "4",
"opb": "5",
"opc": "3",
"opd": "2",
"correctanswer": "1"
},
 {
     "qno": 3,
"question": "What is the mean of these numbers: 10, 20, 30, 40, 50?",
"opa": "25",
"opb": "30",
"opc": "40",
"opd": "50",
"correctanswer": "2"
},
 {
     "qno": 4,
"question": "A man walks 3 km north, then turns east and walks 4 km. What is the shortest distance from his starting point?",
"opa": "5 km", 
"opb": "7 km",
"opc": "6 km",
"opd": "1 km",
"correctanswer": "1"
},
 {
     "qno": 5,
"question": " Which of the following is a rational number?",
"opa": "√2",
"opb": "π",
"opc": "3/5",
"opd": "√3",
"correctanswer": "3"
},
 {
     "qno": 6,
"question": "If a:b = 2:3 and b:c = 4:5, then what is a:c?",
"opa": " 8:15",
"opb": "3:4",
"opc": "2:5",
"opd": "4:6",
"correctanswer": "1"
},
 {
     "qno": 7,
"question": "The value of (−3) × (−5) × (2) is:",
"opa": "-30",
"opb": "30",
"opc": "-10",
"opd": "10",
"correctanswer": "2"
},
 {
     "qno": 8,
"question": "If 3(x − 2) = 12, then x = ?",
"opa": "6",
"opb": "5",
"opc": "8",
"opd": "4",
"correctanswer": "3"
},
 {
     "qno": 9,
"question": "What is the square root of 225?",
"opa": "12",
"opb": "14",
"opc": "15",
"opd": "16",
"correctanswer": "3"
},
 {
     "qno": 10,
"question": "Simplify: (2/3) + (4/5)",
"opa": "6/15",
"opb": "22/15",
"opc": "14/15",
"opd": " 10/8",
"correctanswer": "2"
} 
]
